Guide to the Yearbook collection ARCH149
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Yearbook collection
1941-2019
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH149
28.7 Linear Feet (167 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies
Some yearbooks may have circulating copies available at Mortensen Library. Digitized/digital copies of some yearbooks are available through MDID at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu/explore/explore/?c=allcollections:70.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of yearbooks for the University of Hartford, as well as its schools and colleges. Some of the yearbooks in the collection belong to Hillyer College, Hartt College of Music, and the Hartford College for Women before they were part of the University of Hartford. The collection also includes one yearbook from University High School, a magnet school located on the University's campus.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into six series by school in chronological order: I. Hillyer Junior College and Hillyer College, 1941-1957; II. Hartford College for Women, 1944-1998; III. Hartt College of Music, 1952-1957; IV. Ward School of Electronics, 1958-1963; V. University of Hartford, 1958-2019; and VI. University High School, 2008.
school yearbooks; Student publications; University of Hartford -- Students; Hartford College; Hartford College for Women; Hartford Junior College; Hartt College of Music; Hillyer College; Hillyer Junior College; University of Hartford; Ward School of Electronics; University High School of Science and Engineering (Hartford, Conn.)
- Hillyer Junior College and Hillyer College, 1941-1957; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of copies of The Vanguard, the yearbook of Hillyer Junior College and Hillyer College, before Hillyer became part of the University of Hartford.
  - The Vanguard, 1941; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1941, Box 1)
  - The Vanguard, 1942; 1 Volumes (Volume Hillyer 1942)
  - The Vanguard, 1943; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1943, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1944; 8 Volumes Duplicates, 2 hardcover (with brown paper wrapping), 1 hardcover (no wrapping), 3 softcover with red comb binding, 2 softcover with black comb binding. (Volume Hillyer 1944 red comb binding, Box 1, Volume Hillyer 1944 black comb binding, Volume Hillyer 1944 hardcover)
  - The Vanguard, 1945; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1945, Box 1)
  - The Vanguard, 1946; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1946, Box 1)
  - The Vanguard, 1947; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1947, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1948; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1948, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1949; 3 Volumes Duplicates; The reading room copy of the 1949 Vanguard includes pages three and four. All other copies of this yearbook have been found with this leaf removed. The scanned version of the yearbook includes these pages. (Volume Hillyer 1949, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1950; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1950, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1951; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1951, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1952; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1952, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1953; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1953, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1954; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1954, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1955; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1955, Box 3)
  - The Vanguard, 1956; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hillyer 1956, Box 4)
  - The Vanguard, 1957; 3 Volumes (Volume Hillyer 1957, Box 4)
- Hartford College for Women, 1944-1998; Series II
  This series contains copies of The Highlander, the yearbook of Hartford College for Women, both before and after it became part of the University of Hartford.
  - The Highlander, 1944; 1 Volumes (Volume HCW 1944)
  - The Highlander, 1945; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1945, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1946; 1 Volumes (Volume HCW 1946)
  - The Highlander, 1947; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1947, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1948; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1948, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1949; 1 Volumes (Volume HCW 1949)
  - The Highlander, 1950; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1950, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1951; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1951, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1952; 1 Volumes (Volume HCW 1952)
  - The Highlander, 1953; 1 Volumes (Volume HCW 1953)
  - The Highlander, 1954; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1954, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1955; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1955, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1956; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1956, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1957; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1957, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1958; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1958, Box 1)
  - The Highlander, 1959; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1959, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1960; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1960, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1961; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1961, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1962; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1962, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1963; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1963, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1964; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1964, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1965; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1965, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1966; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1966, Box 2)
  - The Highlander, 1967; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1967, Box 4)
  - The Highlander, 1968; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1968, Box 4)
  - The Highlander, 1969; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1969, Box 4)
  - The Highlander, 1970; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1970, Box 4)
  - The Highlander, 1971; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1971, Box 4)
  - The Highlander, 1972; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1972, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1973; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1973, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1974; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1974, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1975; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1975, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1976; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1976, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1977; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1977, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1978; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1978, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1979; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1979, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1980; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1980, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1981; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1981, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1982; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1982, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1983; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1983, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1984; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1984, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1985; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1985, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1986; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1986, Box 5)
  - The Highlander, 1987; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1987, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1988; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1988, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1989; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1989, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1990; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1990, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1995; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1995, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1996; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1996, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1997; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1997, Box 6)
  - The Highlander, 1998; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume HCW 1998, Box 6)
- Hartt College of Music, 1952-1957; Series III
  The series contains copies of Allegro, the yearbook of the Hartt College of Music, before it became part of the University of Hartford.
  - Allegro, 1952; 1 Volumes (Volume Hartt 1952)
  - Allegro, 1953; 1 Volumes (Volume Hartt 1953)
  - Allegro, 1954; 2 Volumes Duplicates; 1 Files 2 Ad rate forms; 111.5 Megabytes (Volume Hartt 1954, Box Shared Document Box 1, Box 4)
  - Allegro, 1955; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hartt 1955, Box 4)
  - Allegro, 1956; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hartt 1956, Box 4)
  - Allegro, 1957; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Hartt 1957, Box 4)
- Ward School of Electronics, 1958-1963; Series IV
  - Explorer, 1958; 1 Volumes (Volume Ward 1958)
  - Explorer, 1959; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Ward 1959, Box 4)
  - Explorer, 1962; 1 Volumes (Volume Ward 1962)
  - Explorer, 1963; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Ward 1963, Box 4)
- University of Hartford, 1958-2019; Series V
  This series contains the yearbooks and a few yearbook supplements of the University of Hartford's yearbook, from 1958-2019.
  - Primus, 1958; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1958, Box 6)
  - Primus, 1959; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1959, Box 6)
  - Primus, 1960; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1960, Box 6)
  - Primus, 1961; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1961, Box 6)
  - Primus, 1962; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1962, Box 6)
  - Primus, 1963; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1963, Box 6, Box 7)
  - Primus, 1964; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1964, Box 7)
  - Primus, 1965; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1965, Box 7)
  - Primus, 1966; 3 Volumes Duplicates; 1 Folders (Volume Univ. 1966, Box 7)
  - Primus, 1967; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1967, Box 7)
    General
    On page 166 of the 1967 Yearbook, Gail E. Fenn's photograph appears under the name Mary Jane Everett, and according to alumni from that class, Mary Jane Everett's image was labelled as Gail E. Fenn. The information pertaining to each student on the left side of the page was not switched and appears to be correct for each student.
  - Primus, 1968; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1968, Box 7)
  - 69, 1969; 3 Volumes (Volume Univ. 1969, Volume 0207303179254, Volume 0207303179262)
  - University of Hartford, 1970; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1970, Box 2)
  - Hartford, 1971; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1971, Volume 0207303179270)
  - Reunion (supplement), 1971; 1 Volumes (Volume Univ. Sup. 1971)
  - Jacks, 1972; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1972, Box 7)
  - YEARbook, 1973; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1973, Box 7)
  - Yourbook, 1974; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1974, Box 8)
  - Yourbook, 1975; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1975, Box 8)
  - Yourbook, 1976; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1976, Box 8)
  - Paradigm, 1977; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1977, Box 8)
  - U of H, 1978; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1978, Box 8)
  - Book of Faces, 1979; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1979, Box 8)
  - The University of Hartford (Yearbook Supplement), 1979; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. Sup. 1979, Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Legacy, 1980; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1980, Box 8)
  - Primus, 1981; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1981, Box 8)
  - Primus Supplement, 1981; 1 Volumes (Volume Univ. Sup. 1981)
  - Primus, 1982; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1982, Box 8)
  - Primus, 1983; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1983, Box 8)
  - Primus Supplement, 1983; 1 Volumes (Volume Univ. Sup. 1983)
  - Primus, 1984; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1984, Box 9)
  - Primus Supplement, 1984; 2 Volumes Duplicates, One copy has graffiti on the cover (Volume Univ. Sup. 1984, Box 9)
  - Primus, 1985; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1985, Box 9)
  - Primus Supplement, 1985; 4 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1985, Box 9)
  - Icon, 1986; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1986, Box 9)
  - Icon, 1987; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1987, Box 9)
  - Icon, 1988; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1988, Box 9)
  - Icon, 1989; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1989, Box 9)
  - Icon, 1990; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1990, Box 9)
  - Icon, 1991; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1991, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1992; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1992, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1993; 3 Volumes Dark tan cover; 3 Volumes Light tan cover (Volume Univ. 1993 dark tan cover, Volume Univ. 1993 light tan cover, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1994; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1994, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1995; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1995, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1996; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1996, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1997; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1997, Box 10)
  - Icon, 1998; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1998, Box 11)
  - Icon, 1999; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 1999, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2000; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2000, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2001; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2001, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2002; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2002, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2003; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2003, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2004; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2004, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2005; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2005, Box 11)
  - Icon, 2006; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2006, Box 11, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2007; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2007, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2008; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2008, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2009; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2009, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2010; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2010, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2011; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2011, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2012; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2012, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2013; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2013, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2014; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2014, Box 12)
  - Icon, 2015; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2015, Box 13)
  - Icon, 2016; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2016, Box 13)
  - Icon, 2017; 3 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2017, Box 13)
  - Icon, 2018; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. 2018, Box 13)
  - Icon, 2019; 2 Volumes duplicates (Object Univ. 2019, Box 13)
- University High School, 2008; Series VI; 2 Volumes Duplicates (Volume Univ. HS, 2008, Box 6)
  This series only contains copies of the 2008 University High School yearbook.